能不能
Can't you--
Can't--
告诉我这到底有多严重
Just at least tell me how serious it is.
这辆被偷的车是怎么回事
What's with the stripped cab?
保安也纳闷同样的问题
Security guard wondered the same thing.
然后就发现了这具尸体
That's when he came across the body.
死者是谁
Who's our victim?
阿米尔·阿哈比  出租车司机
Amir Alhabi, taxi driver.
好  联系汽车偷盗调查部门
All right. Contact Auto Theft.
让他们留意这辆车被偷的零件
Have 'em on the lookout for these stolen car parts.
已经联系了
Already done.
死者携带有现金吗
Was there money on the body?
身上没有  车上也没有
Not on the body, not in the cab.
所有证据显示这是为财谋杀
Everything points to him being popped for cash and car parts.
宝贝  也不全是
Not everything, baby.
-你刚叫他宝贝吗  -有吗
- Did you just call him baby? - Ooh, did I?
发现什么异常情况了吗
Anyway, you found something unusual?
现在有了  死亡时间和抢劫时间吻合
Not at first. Time of death fits a robbery.
死者在11点15分被杀
He was killed at 11:15.
时间如此精确  佩服
So specific. I'm impressed.
他摔倒时表坏了
His watch broke when he fell.
真不该告诉我这个  没那么佩服了
Ah, you shouldn't have told me. Less impressed.
死亡原因也相吻合
Cause of death fits, too.
一颗9毫米口径子弹击中脑部致死
Looks like a 9-millimeter to the noggin.
但是有一点并不吻合
But there's something that doesn't fit.
他的手指  接连断裂
His fingers... were broken one at a time.
的哥们有时把钱藏起来
Cabbies sometimes hide their money.
也许是凶手折磨他  逼他说出藏钱之处
Maybe they tortured him to tell them where the money was.
查一下他的行车地点
All right, let's find out where he was driving
以及临死前搭载的乘客
and who he picked up before he wound up here.
阿米尔·阿哈比
Amir Alhabi--
是一个成功移民实例
He's a real immigrant success story.
七年前从叙利亚来到美国
Came over from Syria seven years ago
去年六月成为美国公民
became a citizen last June.
据出租车管理协会消息称
According to the taxi and limo commission,
他和表兄杰马尔共同拥有这辆车和相关许可
he owned his cab and medallion with a cousin--Jamal.
呃  好的
Um... Right.
管理协会应该知道阿米尔昨天在哪吧
W-well, T.L.C. would know where Amir was, right?
他们监控出租车吧
They track cabs?
只有在计价器开启的情况下
Only when the meter is running.
昨天10点2分阿米尔关掉了计价器
Amir shut his off at 10:02 p.m.
没办法查明他死前去了哪吗
So there's no way to tell where he went before he died.
实际上  有办法
Actually, there is.
阿米尔订了一个全球定位追踪服务
Amir subscribed to a GPS tracking service.
用来帮助的哥们标出最佳
It helps cabbies map out the best place
拉客地点  等等之类的
to troll for fares, stuff like that.
阿米尔关掉计价器之后
Anyway, after Amir shut off his meter,
驶向华盛顿高地
he drove up to Washington heights.
在圣尼古拉斯大街1600号停下
He parked in the 1600 block of St. Nicholas Avenue
六分钟以后  计价器又运行
for six minutes, motor running,
他就开向了仓库
then he drove to the warehouse.
那个时间的华盛顿高地
Okay, Washington heights is a shady place
人员混杂  如果他关闭计价器
that time of night, and if he turned off his meter,
-肯定不是拉生意  -也许他被打劫
- he wasn't looking for a fare. - Maybe he was carjacked
被迫开车到仓库去
and forced to drive to that warehouse.
让便衣去排查那个地方
All right, have unis canvass the area.
看有没有人见过死者
See if anyone remembers seeing him.
他最后的电话打给谁的
What about his last phone call?
10点01分打给他老婆纳兹哈·阿哈比
10:01 to his wife-- Nazihah Alhabi.
去看看
Okay. Let's go.
其实手机上还有个东西
Actually, there was one more thing on the phone.
阿米尔开启了记事本功能
Amir opened a notebook application,
写下了这个
And he, uh, wrote down this.
C4121652
Uh, "C4121652,"
死者是在死前一个小时写下的
And it was written down just about an hour before he died.
这不是车牌号
And it's not a license tag.
查一下  看能不能查明白
All right. See if you can figure it out.
我知道了  七个数字  是个电话号码
I got it. Seven digits-- it's a phone number.
"C"是号码拥有者的姓名缩写
"C" is the initial of the person to whom it belongs.
我已经查过了
I already tried that.
所有纽约的区号都试过了吗
With all the new york area codes?
-对  -有意思  也许...
- Yeah. - Intriguing. Maybe--
-卡塞尔  -来了
- Castle. - Coming.
阿哈比夫人
Mrs. Alhabi,
我们知道昨天十点阿米尔给你打过电话
We understand that Amir called you at 10:00.
-你们说了什么  -他说会晚回家
- What did the two of you talk about? - Just that he'd be late.
人们都从百老汇剧院刚出来
The plays were getting out on Broadway,
他想再多拉点活
and he wanted to pick up more fares.
实际上  他没拉活  他关掉了计价器
Actually, he didn't do that. He turned his meter off
去了华盛顿高地
and he went up to Washington heights.
那里常有毒品交易和卖淫嫖娼
That part of town is known for drug dealing and prostitution.
不  他不会做这种事的
No, he would never do such things.
杰马尔  谢谢
Jamal, thank you.
阿米尔的手机上还有一个记录
Uh, there was an annotation on Amir's phone.
知道是什么吗
Do you have any idea what this is?
C4121652
"C4121652."
不知道  我以为这是一起抢劫案
No, I-I thought this was a robbery, that he was robbed.
是  不过任何其他小线索也可能有干系
It was. It's just, any minor detail might be relevant.
他最近怎么样
How did he seem lately?
为钱所困扰
Worried about money.
玛丽卡  我们的女儿  需要做手术
Malika, our daughter, she needed surgery.
非常的难熬
It's been very hard.
她永远也见不到自己的爸爸了
She'll never know her father.
恕我失陪
Please excuse me.
杰马尔  你和阿米尔是生意伙伴吗
Jamal, you and Amir were business partners?
近来生意怎么样
How was the business doing?
单靠开出租是发不了财的
You don't get rich driving a cab,
但是我们赚到钱了
but we made money.
阿米尔开车  轮班时把车租给别人开
Amir drove, and we rented shifts to other drivers.
他们是谁
And who were they?
凯文·麦凯恩和德米特里·沃多夫
Uh, Kevin Mccann and, uh, Dimitri Voldov.
你不开车
So you didn't drive the cab?
对我来说  出租车只是一种投资
For me, the taxi medallion was an investment.
我刚做起了新生意  开了个搬家公司
I just started a new business, a moving company.
出租车管理协会并不会派发很多许可
T.L.C. doesn't issue a lot of medallions.
这可是一笔小财富
It would've been worth a small fortune.
谁继承阿米尔的股份
So who inherits Amir's share?
纳兹哈  她需要这些
Nazihah will. She'll need it.
不好意思  贝克特
Excuse me. Beckett.
汽车偷盗监察部门查到了丢失的汽车零件
Auto theft got a hit on the stolen car parts.
一个叫里曼·琼斯的人在地下拆车厂销赃
A guy named Leeman Jones was selling 'em at a chop shop.
零件上的识别码和事故车辆吻合
V.I.N. number on the parts matches our cab.
-琼斯现在哪  -审问室
- Where's jones now? - Interrogation.
那些汽车配件是我捡的
I found those car parts.
在被你偷的车上
On the car that you stripped.
我们有目击证人看到你了
We have a witness who places you at the scene,
所以别想再玩什么花样
So please just stop with the lying.
目击证人
A witness?
我是偷了那辆车  我就是干这行的
Okay, I stripped that taxi. It's what I do.
-在你杀死了司机后  -什么
- After you killed the driver. - After I what?
不  我没杀人  因为里面根本没有人
No, I didn't kill any driver 'cause there was no driver.
他被弃在仓库
He was left in the warehouse.
洗劫一空  一枪致命
Robbed and shot in the head.
不是我干的
Well, not by me, okay?
我在开车  看到有一辆空车  我想
I was cruisin' and I saw the cab sitting empty, and I figure,
没理由让好零件废弃掉啊
no sense in letting good parts go to waste.
当时什么时间
What time was that?
不清楚  大概11点15分
I don't know. About 11:15 probably.
正好是死者的死亡时间
Well, there you go. That's right when he died.
听着  不是的  我不伤害别人
Look, no. I don't hurt people.
我只倒卖汽车
I'm just a car guy.
肯定是那个目击证人干的  一定是
Your witness must've done it. That's it.
他就是在那假装是无辜的路人
And now he's just playing innocent bystander or something.
没有目击证人
There was no witness.
你说什么
What do you mean?
-我在吓唬你  -吓唬我
- I was bluffing. - Bluffing?
-对  -不
- Yes. - No.
她有权这么做  真奇怪你竟然不知道
She's allowed to do that. I'm surprised you don't know that.
不  我是说当时有个人在那里
No, I mean there was a guy there.
-我看见他了  -什么人  描述一下
- I saw him. What guy? - Describe him.
我没看清  我停下车来  他就跑了
I didn't get a clear look. He ran off when I pulled up.
可是他当时在那
But he was there.
他在车里找什么东西
He was there looking for something in the car.
为什么这么说
What makes you say that?
他在车里毁坏了东西
Because he did a number on the interior.
他把内饰都撕破了
He tore up the upholstery.
你认为他说实话了吗
Think he's telling the truth?
他还没那种临场发挥的本事
That guy does not have the improv skills
-编造这种谎言  -让鉴证组检查汽车
- to make up a lie like that. - Have C.S.U. check the car
-查找毁坏之处  -明白
- for signs that someone else tampered with it. - You got it.
不好意思  接个电话
Uh... Sorry, you guys. I gotta get this.
待会再说  莱恩
Not now, Ryan. Uh--
她怎么了
What's going on with her?
你知道她的  自己的事从来都闭口不谈
You know Beckett. She plays it close to the vest.
我和一名从阿米尔那里
So I, uh, spoke
租车的一名司机谈了谈
to one of the drivers who rents a shift with Amir's cab.
-凯文·麦凯恩  -不  是另一个  德米特里·沃多夫
- Kevin Mccann. - Uh, no, the other one-- Dimitri Voldov.
他有不在场证据
He alibied out,
不过有关麦凯恩他说了很多
but he had lots to say about Mccann.
麦凯恩和阿米尔两天前大吵了一架
Him and Amir got in a major fight two days ago.
-为什么  -德米特里不知道
- About what? - Well, Dimitri didn't know.
但是阿米尔说要开除他
But amir told him he was gonna fire Mccann.
麦凯恩现在在哪
And where's Mccann now?
在联盟出租车公司上班呢
Renting a shift at Allied Taxi
那  那我告诉她
So I'll-- I'll tell Beckett that.
你吗  那最好了
Could you? That'd be best.
我们是吵过架  可这也没违法  对吗
Amir and I had words. No law against that, right?
昨晚11点15分你在做什么
Where were you last night at 11:15?
在这辆车里
In this cab
拉着醉酒的证券交易员
driving a drunk bond trader
去上西区   怎么了
to the upper west. Why?
那个时间阿米尔被杀害了
Well, because that's when he was murdered.
开玩笑吧
Oh, you're kidding me.
听着  我没伤害过他
Look, I didn't lay a hand on that guy.
两天前你们为什么打架
Why did you and he fight two days ago?
因为他催我交租金
Because he was raping me on rent.
他负担的起的
Look, the guy could afford it.
他当时带着一大笔钱
He was flashing a roll that could choke a horse.
有5000美元呢
Had 5 grand, easy.
他经常带这么多钱在身上吗
Wait. Was he known for carrying around that much money?
我是第一次看见
First I saw of it.
完事了吗  我要出车了
Look, um, are we done here? Because my meter's running.
如果阿米尔连医药费都拿不起
If Amir was struggling to pay medical bills...
-他拿那么一大笔钱做什么用  -是埃斯波西托
- what was he doing with that much cash? - It's Esposito.
他需要我们俩马上回到犯罪现场
He needs us back at the crime scene asap.
记得里曼·琼斯说过是其他人
Remember Leeman Jones said that some other dude
-把车破坏过吗  -嗯
- messed with the cab? - Uh-huh.
鉴证组刚刚查明了原因
Well, C.S.U. just figured out why.
那辆车安装了摄像头
The car had cameras.
是针孔摄像头  还有麦克风
Pinhole cameras, microphones, too.
太好了  我们只要把带子倒到昨晚
Great. All we have to do is rewind to last night,
-看看是谁杀了他  案子就结了  -看不了了
- see who was after him, case closed.- We can't.
他们把装有视频资料的硬盘扯掉了
They ripped out the hard drives with all the video data.
这案子到底是怎么回事
What the hell is going on here?
翻译：东方  咖啡十三  小易  落末一地  大卫熊
时间轴：Jimmy贝壳   陈易   后期：瓜瓜   校对&总监：大卫熊
奇怪的是  阿米尔的妻子
Strange thing is, Amir's wife,
他的表兄  还有其他司机们
his cousin, other drivers--
没有人知道他装了那些摄像头
none of them knew that he'd installed those cameras.
也许阿米尔参加了一个真人秀
Maybe Amir was doing a reality show.
没错  我也这么想  但结果并不是这样
See, I thought that, too, but turns out, no.
而且它们也不是执法部门要求安装的
And they weren't installed by law enforcement either.
你觉得有人在监视他
You think someone was spying on him.
或者是他的乘客  或者两者皆有
Or his passengers, or both.
也许就像《窃听大阴谋》里那样
Maybe it's like in "The Conversation",
他无意间窃听到了一场谋杀计划
and he overheard a murder plot.
不管怎样  那里面疑团不少
Whatever it is, it's juicy.
你有没有跟你爸说
Have, you, uh, have you talked to your father
-关于我们旅行的事  -还没有
- about our little trip? - Not yet.
那你还等什么呀
Well, what are you waiting for?
我在宁静绿洲成功地弄到了两个
I have scored two incredibly-hard-to-get spots
很难得到的位子
at the oasis of serenity.
很棒嘛
That's fantastic.
-那是什么  -你没听说过宁静绿洲吗
- What is that? - You haven't heard of the serenity?
-是一个灵修度假村  -它坐落于卡茨基尔山脉
- It's a spiritual retreat.- Oh, it's nestled in the Catskills.
它真是一座圣所  一个让人反思的地方
It's a sanctuary, a place for reflection,
和自己的内心交流
getting in touch with your inner self.
对你来说  那样做合适吗
Well, in--in your case, is that wise?
奶奶为了准备
Gram wants to shed her ego
她的表演课程想要先摆脱自我
in preparation for teaching her acting classes.
没错  做这种事和阿丽克西斯一起最好不过了
Yes, and who better to do that with than Alexis?
我们会住在豪华圆顶帐篷里
We will stay in luxury yurts,
我们还会上冥想课
we will have meditation classes,
和瑜伽课  我们明天晚上就走
yoga classes. We go tomorrow night.
-如果你允许她去的话  -我觉得
- That is, if you will allow her. - Oh, well, I suppose...
-物理  -屋里...无力...
- Physics. - fizzy--physic--
是物理  物理考试  你不是有物理考试吗
Physics. Physics exam. Don't you have a physics exam?
我的物理考试  我差点忘了
My--my physics exam. I almost forgot.
周一早上就考  我还没怎么复习
It's on Monday morning. I haven't studied.
而且它占成绩的20%
And it counts for 20% of my grade.
20%啊
20%.
把握今日  及时行乐[出自贺拉斯的一首颂诗]
Carpe diem. Seize the day.
我显然我没这么教导我的儿子
Clearly I didn't teach that to my son.
好吧  亲爱的  改日吧
All right, darling. Well, another time.
看来我得靠自己来发掘自我了
I guess I will just have to find my inner self by myself.
我能行的
Mm. I can do it.
史上最好的老爸
Best dad ever.
没错  我明白
Yeah, I get that.
有时候  你在这儿的话
And once in a while, if you were here,
会很不错的
that would be great.
我们等会再谈好吗
Can we do this later?
拜拜
Bye.
什么风把你的机车男孩吹来了
What brings motorcycle boy here?
是机车男孩大夫
Doctor motorcycle boy.
-他来还需要理由吗  -看起来是很私人的问题
- Does he need a reason? - It just looked personal.
的确是  那些秘密摄像头查的怎么样了
It was. Where are we on those hidden cameras?
只知道是个专业人士安装的  技术小组正在
Just that they were installed by a pro. Techs are running
查序列号  以便找到他们是从哪来的了
the serial numbers now to find out where they came from.
一个出租车里有监视器
A guy with surveillance in his cab,
又携带大量现金的家伙  这案子很可疑
too much money in his pocket-- the whole thing feels hinky.
他的财政状况也很可疑
Based on his financials, it looks hinky, too.
这家伙背着一屁股的医药费没法支付
Guy had medical bills up the wazoo.
但五天前出现了这个
But then there's this from five days ago.
存入一万美元现金
A cash deposit for $10,000?
一个生活困难的出租车司机拿这笔钱做什么
What's a struggling cab driver doing with that kind of cash?
我发现了一些奇怪的事
Yo. I just found something weird.
我为了查出他死那天都去过哪里
I logged in to Amir's GPS account
登陆了阿米尔的全球定位账户
to track where he drove the day he died.
下午4点07分  阿米尔在15街和美洲大街的交汇处
At 4:07 P.M., Amir picked up a cash fare
接了一位支付现金的客人
at 15th and Avenue of the Americas.
那有什么奇怪的
What's weird about that?
乘客坐了二十六分钟的车之后  在阿米尔
Well, the passenger rode for 26 minutes, then got dropped off
接他的同一地点又下车了
at the same corner where Amir picked him up.
谁会花三十美元只为了兜圈子
Now who would pay 30 bucks to go in a circle?
想和阿米尔谈话的人
Someone who wanted to talk to Amir.
查查那些交通摄像头  看看我们能不能
Check those traffic cameras. See if we can get a look
-看到乘客的脸  -这就去  长官
- at that passenger. - On it, captain.
长官
Sir.
我们找到了阿米尔车里那些秘密摄像头的来源
We got a match on those cameras hidden in Amir's cab.
摄像头是一周之前由泰普诺公司订的货
Cameras were ordered a week ago by a Techno-Pro Systems.
我不知道你们在说什么
I don't know what you guys are talking about.
我没安装任何秘密摄像头
I didn't install any hidden cameras.
你的名字在采购订单上
Your name's on the purchase order.
是你自己签名的
As is your signature.
你违犯了隐私期望法令
You violated the expectation of privacy act.
你知道我可以因此逮捕你吗
Do you know that I can arrest you for that?
-是的  不  -或者你直接告诉我们
- Ohh. Yeah. I mean-- I mean, no. - Or you could just tell her
谁雇了你安装那些监视设备
who hired you to install the surveillance equipment.
-我向他承诺我会保密的  -谁雇了你
- I promised him I'd keep it on the D.L. - Who hired you?
阿米尔·阿哈比
Amir Alhabi.
你为阿米尔安装的这些东西吗
You put it in for Amir?
-没错  -他为何要给自己的出租车安装摄像头
- Yeah. - Why would he have you put cameras in his cab?
安全起见
Security reasons.
他就这么说的
That's all he said.
长官
Yo, cap.
在阿米尔让那人下车的地方的交通摄像头上
Caught a break on our mystery passenger--
查到了那个神秘乘客
off a traffic cam near where Amir dropped the guy off.
注意到什么了吗
Notice anything?
-他带着枪  -没错  而且他不是警察
- He's carrying. - Yeah, and he's not police.
-西装太高档了  -在这个位置挨家排查
- Suit's way too fancy. - Canvass where this was taken.
看看有没有人认识他
See if anyone knows who he is.
我一直对出租车的花费有记录
I keep track of the expenses for the cab.
-没有买摄像头的账单  -那一万美元呢
- There was never any bill for cameras.- What about the $10,000?
我也是今天才得知这笔钱的事
The first time I heard about the money is today.
我实在无法想象它们是从哪来的
I can't imagine where it came from.
钱  摄像头  华盛顿高地  纳兹哈
Money, cameras, Washington Heights--Nazihah,
你丈夫很显然对你有所隐瞒
your husband was clearly hiding something from you.
你知道这有可能是什么事吗
Do you have any idea what it was?
不  我完全不清楚
No. No, I don't understand this at all.
好吧  你认识这个男人吗
Okay. Do you recognize this man?
-他坐过你丈夫的出租车  -认识
- He rode in your husband's cab. - Yes.
认识  他来过这
Y-yes, he was here.
-什么时候  -上个礼拜
- When? - Last week.
-他和阿米尔在街上谈话  -他是谁
- He and Amir were talking in the street. - Who was he?
我问过阿米尔  他说那个男人
I asked Amir. He said that the man
认错人了
had mistaken him for someone else.
阿米尔明显认识那个人  他为什么对她撒谎
Amir clearly knew the guy. Why would he lie to her?
他为什么在那家伙坐他车的同一天
And how does he end up dead
-死掉了呢  -贝克特
- the same day this guy rides in his cab? - Beckett.
我们在排查时查出了神秘乘客的身份
We just got a hit on our canvass for the mystery passenger.
查出叫什么名了吗
We got a name on that face?
还没有  但他是14街咖啡店的忠实顾客
Not yet, He's a big fan of this coffee shop on 14th.
他每天下午两点都去那喝一杯浓缩咖啡
He shows up every afternoon for an espresso at 2:00.
先生
Sir.
穿乳白色西服那位  站住
In the cream suit--stop!
纽约警局的  转过身来
NYPD. Turn around.
和凶器一样是9毫米口径的
It's a 9-millimeter just like our murder weapon.
你有隐蔽武器许可证吗
You have a concealed weapons permit?
在我夹克左口袋里
Inside left pocket of my jacket,
和我的证件放在一起
along with my credentials.
法里克·尤瑟夫
Fariq Yusef.
叙利亚领事馆
Syrian consulate.
乐意为您效劳
At your service.
把手放下吧
Put your hands down.
-谢谢  -两天前
- Thank you. - Two days ago,
你坐了阿米尔·阿哈比的出租车
you were driving in a cab with Amir Alhabi.
-他被谋杀了  -听闻此事  我很难过
- He's been murdered. - I am saddened to hear that.
你在那辆出租车里坐了半小时
You were in that cab for half an hour.
你们俩到底是什么关系
What's the nature of your relationship?
我有外交赦免权
I... I have diplomatic immunity.
-你没有问问题...  -谁杀了他  是你吗
- You have no standing questioning... - Who killed him? Was it you?
-或拘留我的权力  -回答我的问题  是你杀了他吗
- or detaining me. - Answer my question. Did you kill him?
我想要回我的手枪  麻烦你
I'd like my pistol, please.
你可以来第12分局取
You can collect it at the 12th precinct.
我会的
And so I shall.
法里克·尤瑟夫在领事馆的头衔是
Fariq Yusef's official title at the consulate
安全总管
is head of security.
他是一位秘密警察
He's a member of the secret police.
他可能以前敲碎过别人的手指
Well, he's probably broken a few fingers in his day.
尤瑟夫有一把9毫米的手枪
And Yusef also owned a 9-millimeter gun,
正好和杀死阿米尔的是同一型号
which was the same kind of gun that killed Amir.
也许尤瑟夫将阿米尔招致麾下
Maybe Yusef recruited Amir,
让他从事秘密的谍报行动
drew him in to the shadowy world of espionage.
一旦他完成任务  他的命运便从此被尘封
Once he finished his mission, his fate was sealed.
尤瑟夫为了封口把他杀了  然后拿走了
Yusef killed him to tie up loose ends, and then took
揭露他们之间秘密关系的数据硬盘
the data drive containing the explosive revelations.
那关系具体是指什么
And that would be what exactly?
我依然在构思那部分  但这的确合情合理
I'm still thinking on that. But it's a perfect fit.
没错  除非法里克·尤瑟夫并不是凶手
Yeah, except that Fariq Yusef isn't the killer.
你确定吗  因为那会毁掉一个十分完美的假设
Are you sure? Because that would ruin a perfectly good theory.
我确定  阿米尔被杀的那天晚上
Yeah. The night Amir was killed,
法里克和叙利亚大使在一起
Fariq was with the Syrian ambassador
在贝内特球场看球赛
at a soccer game at Bennett field.
网上有照片可以证明
There are photos online to prove it.
这又让我们回到了原点
Which brings us back to square one.
好吧  阿米尔和尤瑟夫去了曼哈顿南区转了一圈
Okay, so Amir and Yusef take a tour of lower Manhattan,
不久后的那天夜里
and then later on that same night,
他打给妻子  说他还在工作
He calls his wife, tells her that he's still working,
其实是去了华盛顿高地
and instead, went up to Washington Heights.
接着死在仓库里
Then he ends up dead at the warehouse
数据硬盘也被破坏了
with the data drive ripped out.
C4121652
C4121652.
阿米尔开车到圣尼古拉斯大街1600号
Amir took his cab down St. Nicholas ave to the 1600 block.
他停在大街上
He parked mid-block.
所以呢
so?
所以我在想
So I'm just thinking,
C4121652中的1652是个地址
The 1652 part of C4121652 is an address.
圣尼古拉斯大街1652号是什么地方
What's at St. Nicholas Ave. At 1652?
北曼哈顿仓库
North Manhattan Storage.
C412是个储存室
C412 is a storage unit.
谋杀  政治阴谋
Murder, political intrigue,
金钱交易  现在又有神秘储存室
cash payments, and now a mysterious storage locker?
太棒了
Oh, this is too good.
等等  我们怎么打开呢
Wait. How are we gonna get it open?
无计可施时
well, if all else fails...
我都不好意思提起
For reasons too disturbing to mention,
这太火辣了
I-I find that hot.
或者
Or...
我从阿米尔的物品中拿了钥匙
I grabbed Amir's keys from property,
希望这是他的储存室
so hopefully this is his locker.
的确是  你觉得里面会有什么呢
Which it is. What do you think's in there?
不知道  也许空无一物  就像黑手党老大的金库
I don't know. Might be empty, like Al Capone's Vault.
不是吧  想想在这个情形下
Oh, no. Think of all the amazing things
在储存室里找到的那些财宝吧
that are found in storage units at times like this.
约柜  琼斯博士[《夺宝奇兵》情节]
The Arc of the Covenant, Dr. Jones?
约柜在一个板条箱里
Well, the Arc of the Covenant was in a crate.
塑性炸药
Plastic explosives.
卡塞尔  快走  快走
Castle, get out! Get out!
什么
What?
-快走  - 为什么  我不
- Go! - Why? What--I don't--
卡塞尔  快离开这里  快走
Castle, back away from the door! Get away!
发生什么事  那是什么  凯特
What is going on? What is that thing, Kate?
我是凯特·贝克特探长  警员编号0334
This is detective Kate Beckett, badge number 0-3-3-4.
我受到高强度的辐射
I've been exposed to high levels of radiation.
我们需要紧急救助
We need emergency services right away.
各位  你们不能
Guys, you can't just--
你们不能  告诉我这到底有多严重
You can't--just at least tell me how serious it is!
-他们遭辐射有多严重  -不知道
- How badly did they get hit?  - We don't know.
但帮助他们的最佳方法
But the best way for us to help them
就是继续调查这案子
is to keep working on this case.
被害人拥有这个储存室的钥匙
Now our murder victim had a key to this storage unit,
他远不止出租司机那么简单
so he was into a lot more than driving a taxi.
深入调查阿米尔·阿哈比
Dig deep into Amir Alhabi.
带他妻子和表兄过来
Let's get his wife and his cousin in here.
同时  我会致电叙利亚领事馆
Meanwhile, I'll call the Syrian consulate and find out
查查阿米尔与安全主管联系的原因
why Amir had contact with the head of security.
他们不会跟你们谈的
They won't talk to you.
不管阿哈比涉及什么事件
Whatever Alhabi was into,
叙利亚领事馆都不想受牵连
the Syrians don't want it blowing back on 'em.
请原谅  阁下是
Excuse me. Who are you?
你一定是蒙哥马利队长
You must be Captain Montgomery.
我是马克·法伦  录属国土安全局
I'm Mark Fallon, Department of Homeland Security.
国土安全局派我到这里作联络人
D.H.S. Sent me down here to act as a liaison.
我听说你这里出状况了
I understand you have a situation.
危险品紧急处理小组
Those hazmat teams?
他们每次行动
They're only staying in the building
只在大楼里停留一分钟
for about a minute at a time.
也许只是标准程序
Maybe it's just standard protocol.
是的  也许那里太危险处理不了
Yeah. Maybe it's just too hot in there to handle.
你的辐射探测器
That radiation detector of yours,
上面有刻度吗
does it have a scale on it.
是胸透X光级别还是核电站泄露的级别
You know, like chest x-ray to Chernobyl?
最大值了
Maxed out.
我们要假设阿哈比不是一个人在行动
We have to assume Alhabi wasn't acting alone.
他妻子和表兄在哪里
Where are we on his wife and cousin?
她正过来
She's on her way in.
据邻居讲  杰马尔出去喝酒了
According to a neighbor, Jamal went out drinking.
我们正设法找到他
We're trying to track him down.
这些核原料不是阿米尔自己的
Amir either had the nuclear material for himself
就是他为别人保管的
or he was holding on to it for someone else.
不管怎样  这就是他被杀的原因
Either way, odds are, that's what got him killed.
将他通话记录和恐怖监测名单进行交叉对比
Check his phone records against the terror watch list.
我们已经着手调查了  请原谅
We're already doing that. Excuse me.
只想弄清楚
Just so I'm clear,
你要全面接管吗
are you taking over?
这是你的案子
This is your case.
我只是来尽力协助的
I'm just here to lend support however I can.
队长  移民和海关执法局刚发来
Yo, cap, I.C.E. Just sent over
阿米尔·阿哈比的移民文件
the immigration papers for Amir Alhabi.
他在大马士革一所学校
He got a degree in electrical engineering
获得了电子机械学位
from a school in Damascus.
-他在叙利亚从事什么  -刚得知
- What was he working on in Syria?  - I got that one.
我刚跟国务院的人通过话
I just spoke with the state department.
阿米尔第一次入境的时候他们盘问过他
They debriefed Amir when he first landed here.
他正在从事叙利亚武器项目的工作
They say he was working on a weapons program for the Syrians.
核武器吗
Nuclear weapons?
-是的  -好吧
- Yeah.  - Okay.
现在由我接管
Now I'm taking over.
是个炸弹
It's a bomb.
那储存室里有个核弹
There's a nuclear bomb in that locker.
卡塞尔  我们不知道是个炸弹
Castle, we don't know that it's a bomb.
一爆炸我们就知道了
Well, we will as soon as it goes off,
在我们气化前的十亿分之一秒
in that nanosecond before we're vaporized.
对不起
I'm sorry.
作家的职业病犯了
It's just the--the writer in me
总想到最坏的场景
going to worst-case scenario.
-能说点别的吗  -好的
- Can we just talk about something else?  - Yeah.
乔什怎样了
How's Josh?
还好
Fine.
他
He's, um...
他正在前往海地的路上
He's on his way to Haiti
又去做无国界医生
to do another doctors without borders mission.
要去多久
How long?
我不知道
I don't know.
真可笑  卡塞尔
It's so funny, Castle.
一开始  我喜欢他忙碌的身影
You know, at first, I loved that he was so busy.
只是
It just, um...
这给了我迈出一步的机会
Just gave me an opportunity to keep one foot out the door,
以防万一
Just in case.
但只迈出一步
But with one foot out the door,
很难知道自己的立场在哪
it's hard to know where you stand.
即使我迈出一步  又有什么意义呢
And even if I did, I mean, what does it mean?
他在那里救死扶伤
He's out there. He's saving people.
要我怎么跟那去比呢
How do you even compete with that?
没法比  任何人都比不上
You can't. No. No one can.
这也正是当初他吸引我的地方
That's one of the things that attracted me to him the most--
热情
that... passion,
干劲
that drive.
为什么对方身上吸引你的特质
Why is it that the thing that attracts you to a person
最终总是变成让你抓狂的特质呢
always ends up being that thing that just drives you crazy?
我只希望
I just wish that...
我希望找到一个可以守候我的人
I wish that I had someone who would be there for me,
我可以守候他
and I could be there for him,
两人可以长相厮守
and we could just dive into it together.
你们可以走了
You're free to go.
可以吗
Uh, we are?
辐射怎么办
What about the radiation?
我们在储存室里发现了放射性钴60残留
We found residual traces of cobalt-60 in the storage unit.
还不足以对健康构成威胁
Not enough to cause any health problems.
贝克特探长  卡塞尔
Detective Beckett, Castle.
你们没事  我们真是太高兴了
We're all real glad you two are okay.
谢谢长官  我们也很高兴  我很困惑
Thanks, sir. So are we. I'm confused, though.
这是虚惊一场吗
Is this just a false alarm?
不全是  如果你们还撑得住
Well, not exactly. If you're up to it,
我们真的需要你们协助调查
we really could use you back at the precinct.
详情路上再说
I can fill you in on the way.
那些钴60是哪里来的
Those traces of cobalt-60, where did they come from?
我们认为储存室里还有一个板条箱
We think there was a second crate at the storage unit,
装有大量的钴60
which contained large quantities of cobalt-60.
找到的电线和连接器
We found wire and crimp-on connectors, which leads us
使我们相信那个箱子装满炸药
to believe the crate was outfitted with explosives.
炸弹
A bomb?
核弹
A dirty bomb.
现在在何处
Where is it now?
这正是我们要找的
That's what we're trying to find out.
爸爸  干到这么晚吗
Hey, dad. Late night?
还要回去  我只是回来换衣服
Uh, still going. I just came back to change my clothes.
那再见了
Well, bid my ego adieu.
我要去绿洲了  阿丽克西斯不能去  多亏你了
I am off to the oasis, minus Alexis, thanks to you.
-其实我改主意了  -是吗
- Actually, I changed my mind about that.  - You have?
你改了
You have?
是的  我觉得你们一起相处很重要
Yeah. I think it's important you have time together.
我对你刮目相看
Oh, my faith in you is restored.
爸爸  我的物理考试怎么办  我不能走
Dad, what about my physics test? I can't just leave.
你可以的  带上它们
Yeah, sure you can. Just take 'em with you.
我还没有收拾呢  我不能
I haven't packed or anything. I can't--
亲爱的  那里什么都有的
Honey, everything is provided there.
我们会玩得很开心的
Oh, we're going to have so much fun.
快点  我去拿个包
Come on. Let's get a bag.
去吧  这对你有好处
Go. It'll be-- it'll be good for you.
鉴于这件案子的特殊性
Due to the nature of this case,
我要提醒各位  不要和任何人谈论此事
let me remind you not to discuss it with anyone,
和家人也不能说
not even family.
我们不能泄露消息引起恐慌
We can't afford to have word leak out and cause a panic.
这案子由法伦探员接管
Let me turn this over to agent Fallon.
谢谢  队长  好吧  各位
Thank you, captain. All right, folks.
目前所知的是  阿米尔·阿哈比在C412号储存室
Here's what we know-- Amir Alhabi built a bomb
制作了一个炸弹
in storage unit C412.
这是枚核弹  用来引爆
It's a dirty bomb, designed to explode
并散射高放射性钴60
and disperse highly radioactive cobalt-60...
那枚炸弹不见了
And that bomb is missing...
我打电话给珍妮告诉她我会晚到
I called Jenny to tell her I'd be late.
劝她去她妈妈那里
Tried to get her to go visit her Mom.
我也跟蕾妮说了类似的话
Yeah, I did the same thing with Lanie.
没用的  她恨她妈妈
Didn't work. She hates her Mom.
找员工谈谈  查一下监控录像
... interview facility employees, check surveillance video,
具体情况大家都清楚
You know the drill.
只要找到了取走炸弹的人
We find the person who moved the bomb,
就能很快找到炸弹在哪儿
we'll find where it is.
行动起来
Let's get on it.
卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle.
我对您在此案中的优秀表现表示感谢
I'd like to thank you for your fine work on this case.
但我不能派市民冲锋陷阵
However, I can't have civilians on the front lines.
感觉就像是
It's as though I'm getting a raise
在升职的同时被炒了鱿鱼
and getting fired at the same time.
关键是  这并不是你的工作
Except for, you don't actually work here.
这是为你的安全着想
It's for your own protection.
我在政府的朋友
Well, my friend the governor
听到这话肯定很失望
will be very disappointed to hear it.
好吧
Okay.
尽量别碍事
Just try and stay out of the way.
贝克特探长  说句话
Detective Beckett, a word.
他不信我
He doesn't trust me.
他不信任何人
Or anyone else.
工作本质使然
Nature of the job.
我能做什么
So how can I help?
阿米尔的妻子...
Amir's wife...
她在传讯中表现如何
How did she seem during the interview?
跟所有刚失去丈夫的女人一样
Like a woman who had just lost her husband.
她看上去可信吗
Did she appear truthful?
当时的确很可信
Mm-hmm, at the time she did.
我要你跟我一起进去
I'm gonna want you in there with me, okay?
要让她见到熟人  这很重要
I think it's important she sees a friendly face.
如果我过火了  你就拉我回来
If I go over the line, you just reel me back in.
是个不错的切入点
That's a nice touch.
什么
What?
那个孩子
The baby.
纳兹哈  这位是法伦探员
Nazihah, this is agent Fallon.
阿米尔的案子有新消息吗
Do you have news about Amir's case?
事实上  有新消息
As a matter of fact, I do.
阿米尔账户里的一万美金是通过汇款存入的
That $10,000 was wired into Amir's account.
就是说可以追查来源  打开资金追踪数据库
Which means it can be traced. Pull up the trakfund database
输入银行账号和路径
and put in the routing and account numbers.
刚把C412号储存室过去48小时
Whoa. Just downloaded footage of unit C412
录像下载下来
for the last 48.
希望这个时段拍到有人去过那里
Hopefully that's when somebody stopped by.
阿拉伯恐怖分子  谁信啊
An Arab terrorist. Who'd believe it?
老兄  反过来想
Think back, bro.
我就是这意思  已经想过了
That's my point. It's been done.
-可靠可信  -这次不是
- Which means it's tried and true. - Not this time.
也许跟我们想的不一样
Maybe it's not what we think.
那一万美金由一个叫詹姆斯·史密斯的人
That $10,000 that was wired in, it's from a bank
从密歇根州迪尔伯恩的银行汇来
in Dearborn, Michigan, from a James Smith.
这名字在美国一抓一大把  八成是假名
That's the most common name in America. It's probably bogus.
再说迪尔波恩有很多中东人
Plus, there's a major middle-eastern population in Dearborn.
就在转账前四分钟
Four minutes before it was transferred out,
这笔钱由詹姆斯·史密斯
it was transferred in from...
从德州南方银行转出
James Smith, Texas Southern bank.
汇出这一万美金的人利用多家银行
Whoever sent that 10 grand covered his tracks
反复转汇的方法躲避追踪
by daisy-chaining the money through different banks.
我能找到就说明藏得不太好
Didn't cover them that well if I can follow them.
我打赌阿米尔的妻子身上有线索
Well, I bet Amir's wife could shed some light
希望法伦能
and I hope that Fallon's going
-像杰克·鲍尔那样给力  -也许她不知道
- all Jack Bauer on her ass. - Maybe she didn't know.
他们是一伙的  老兄
They were together, bro.
要是你是恐怖分子  珍妮会不知道吗
Could you be a terrorist without Jenny knowing?
阿米尔不是恐怖分子  他爱他的国家
Amir was not a terrorist. He loved this country.
但他却持有...
And yet he was in possession of...
阿哈比夫人  炸弹在哪里
Where's the bomb, Mrs. Alhabi?
告诉你了  我不知道炸弹的事
I told you, I know nothing about a bomb.
阿米尔不会做这种事的  他没理由
Amir would never do such a thing. Why would he?
他需要钱  你的孩子需要用钱
He needed the cash. That baby of yours is a money pit.
账单越积越厚
The bills started piling up,
他入错了伙
and he got in bed with the wrong people.
我希望你告诉我他们是谁
I need you to tell me who they were.
我发誓我不知道
I swear to you, I don't know.
你怎么会不知道
How can you not know
跟你同床共枕的男人是个恐怖分子
the man you're sharing your bed with is a terrorist?
你也是同谋
You're a part of this!
我没什么好掩藏的
I have nothing to hide.
不  你有  我会找出来的
Yes, you do, and I'm gonna find it.
等我找到了  就把你当做关键证人关起来
And when I do, I'm gonna lock you up as a material witness
-把那孩子送到寄养所去  -你不能那么做
- and send that baby off to foster care. - No, you can't do that.
我能  你等着瞧吧
Oh, yes, I can. Watch me.
先生  我能跟你谈谈吗
Sir, can I talk to you?
-不  来  跟你女儿吻别吧  -求求你
- No. Go ahead. Kiss your daughter good-bye. - Please.
社会服务部门的人就在门口
Social services is right outside that door.
求求你  求求你  你为什么要这么做
Please. Please. Why are you doing this?
纳兹哈  纳兹哈  这名字意为"诚实"对吧
Nazihah, Nazihah, that means "honesty", Right?
你为什么这样  求你  我发誓我不知道
Why are you doing this? Please. I swear to you, I don't know.
"诚实"  是它在阿拉伯语里的意思吧
"Honesty", is that what it means in Arabic?
我再给你一次机会对我说实话
I'm gonna give you one more chance to be honest with me
不然我就把你孩子送走
or I will take your baby away,
-你将再也看不到她  -我说真的
- and you will never see it again. - I swear!
-明白吗  -我发誓
- Do you understand? - I swear to you,
我不知道  我真的不知道
I don't know! I don't know anything!
求你别把她带走
Please don't take her away from me.
她是我的唯一  求你了
She's the only thing I have. Please.
求你了
Please.
好吧
All right.
谁也不会把你的孩子带走
Nobody's gonna take your baby away from you.
给
Here.
没事了
It's okay.
我敢肯定  你能理解我这样做是不得已
You appreciate the tight spot I'm in, I'm sure.
我必须确认你在说实话
I have to be sure you're telling the truth.
贾德探员会送你回家
Agent Geider will drive you home.
你可以走了
You're free to go.
还觉得她可信吗
Still think she's truthful?
我想听听你的意见
I just want your opinion.
可信不可信
Truthful or no?
可信
Yes.
但我的行动还是
But I still have to operate
要建立在她说谎的假设下进行
under the assumption that she's lying.
她接受审讯的时候  我拿到了国家安全许可
While she was in here, I pulled a national security certificate.
她的房子被监听
Her house has just been bugged.
她会受到全天候监控
She'll be under surveillance 24/7.
如果她有所隐瞒  我们会发现的
If she's hiding something, we'll find it.
让她以为我相信她说的是实话
It's important that she believes
这才是重点
I think she's telling the truth.
你做的很好
You did good.
她把你当做盟友
She considers you an ally.
这点回头会很有用
That could be helpful later.
多谢配合  贝克特
Thanks for playing, Beckett.
阿米尔收到的那笔钱
That money that Amir received
总共经过六家银行  但最初是从
was wired through six banks, but originated in
阿富汗汇出的
Afghanistan.
你和贝克特到达前
Whoa. Got a visitor at C412
六小时有人去过C412号储存室
six hours before you and Beckett got there.
这就是我们苦苦寻找的突破
This is the break we've been looking for.
那箱子看上去挺沉
That crate looks heavy.
四周全是铅制护板
It's all the lead shielding.
那是阿米尔的表兄杰马尔
That's Amir's cousin Jamal.
炸弹在他手上
And he has the bomb.
杰马尔·阿哈比
Jamal Alhabi--
他找他表兄做了一个核弹
He had his cousin Amir fashion a dirty bomb
然后杀了他
and then he killed him.
他应该就是我们要找的恐怖小组头目
He's most likely the leader of our terrorist cell.
不到12小时前  他带着炸弹消失了
Now less than 12 hours ago, he disappeared along with the bomb.
现在他
Now at minimum,
至少需要辆货车或越野车来转运
he'd need a van or an S.U.V. to transport it.
杰马尔有家货运公司  检查他的卡车
Jamal owns a moving company, so check his trucks.
把交通录像调出来  查他的财产情况
Pull traffic video, work his financials.
伙计们  我们都住在这儿
Folks, we live here.
我们的家人  我们的挚爱
Our families, our loved ones,
我们的邻居
our neighbors--
不必我说  代价有多大
I don't have to tell you what's at stake.
找到他
Let's find him.
能跟你谈会儿吗
Can I talk to you a second?
行
Yeah.
你怎么看法伦
What's your take on Fallon?
聪明的警察  积极主动  直觉敏锐
Smart cop, driven, killer instinct.
要说他这个人呢  是个混蛋
As a person... kind of a douche.
思路开阔的混蛋吗
Open-minded douche?
不啊  怎么这么问
No. Why?
好故事最重要的是要真实
The key to any good story is authenticity.
是为了读者要把故事写得真实
It's making it feel real for the reader.
这就是为什么作家要下大功夫
That's why writers work so hard
力求细节完美
making the details right.
杰马尔和阿米尔是恐怖分子
Jamal and Amir as terrorists?
细节不对
The details are not right.
但证据充足
Yeah, but the evidence is.
卡塞尔  监控拍下杰马尔推走核弹
Castle, we've got Jamal on video wheeling off a dirty bomb.
他为什么不紧张
Why wasn't he nervous?
为什么每次遇上麻烦他都不慌不忙
Why wasn't he sweating bullets every time he hit a bump?
杰马尔有家货运公司
Jamal owned a moving company.
倘若他不知道箱子里是什么呢
What if he didn't know what was in the crate?
倘若他只不过是被雇来运送的呢
What if he was just hired to pick it up?
倘若他真是冷血杀手呢
What if he's just a cold-blooded killer?
就目前所知  对于这两人
Well, nothing we've learned points to that
-我们均无法断定  -好吧
- with either of these men. - Okay,
阿米尔收到的那笔钱呢
what about that money that Amir received,
就是那笔被追踪到阿富汗的钱
the money that you traced back to Afghanistan?
巴格拉姆空军基地外的一家银行
To a bank outside Bagram Air Base,
通常都是军事人员才在那儿办业务
often used by military personnel.
为什么一个恐怖分子会选那所银行来汇款
Why would a terrorist pick that bank to wire money?
卡塞尔  我们用来打开储存室的钥匙
Castle, the keys that we used to open that storage unit
是阿米尔钥匙链上的
are from Amir's keychain.
凶手也可以把钥匙安在上面啊
The killer could've put the key there.
所有线索都把我们引向阿米尔和杰马尔
All these bread crumbs that have led us to Amir and Jamal,
-如果是他们留给我的呢  -卡塞尔
- what if they were left there for us to find? - Castle--
这里面另有隐情
Something else is going on here.
好吧  你觉得我们应该怎么办
Okay, fine. What would you like us to do?
跟那个对阿米尔有不同看法的人谈谈
Talk to the one person who has a different view of Amir.
但是我需要你的帮助
But I'm gonna need your help.
好了  大家听好了
All right. Listen up.
杰马尔两个月前买了这些卡车
Jamal bought these trucks over two months ago.
这是运送物品
It's a perfect cover
又不被注意的最好伪装
for moving material without anyone noticing.
员工的名单在哪里
Where's the list of his employees?
刚拿到  九个人  都是中东人
Just came in. Nine guys, all middle eastern.
好的  他们可能都是潜伏小组的成员
All right. They're all probably part of the cell.
查查他们去过的地方  然后行动
Let's get their 20s and then move on 'em.
在杰马尔的信用卡消费记录上
Got a purchase on Jamal's credit card
发现他三周前购买了一次性手机
three weeks ago for a burner phone.
查一下  看看能不能调出最近的通话记录
Run it down, see if we can pull up any recent activity.
杰马尔的搬家卡车都停在皇后区的停车场
Jamal's moving trucks are parked in a lot in Queens.
除了一辆五吨卡车  其余的都在
They're all accounted for except for one 5-ton,
记录上显示杰马尔十二小时前把车开走了
and the log says Jamal checked it out 12 hours ago,
没开回来
never brought it back.
他肯定是那辆卡车来运送炸弹
He must have used it to move the crate.
开启预警  我们得找到卡车
Call in that alert. Let's find the truck.
卡塞尔去哪了
Hey, where's Castle?
不知道  出去了吧
I don't know. Must have stepped out.
不管是不是非正式的
Off the record or not,
我为什么要跟你谈论阿米尔·阿哈比
why should I talk to you about Amir Alhabi?
因为你最不希望的事就是
Because the last thing you want is my country
我国认为你们国家在谋划此事
thinking your country's behind this activity.
事实并非如此
Nothing is further from the truth.
那这就可以帮你澄清真相啊
Well, then maybe you can help clear this up.
阿米尔曾在你的核武器小组  他是人才
Amir was in your nuclear program, so he was an asset.
你派人监视他了
You have him watched?
保持消息灵通是我的工作
It's my business to stay informed.
你有看到恐怖主义的苗头吗
Did you ever see any evidence of terrorism?
没有
No.
不过话说回来  我还会有其他的答案吗
But then, what other answer could I give you?
你为什么会去阿米尔家
Why were you at Amir's home?
和他谈谈
To chat with him.
我擅长使用暴力  但是那没有必要
I am adept at violence, but it wasn't called for.
我不时地会与阿米尔见面
I met with Amir from time to time
提醒他别忘本
to remind him of his history.
劝说他回来...
To convince him to come back--
回到武器项目小组
Back to the weapons program.
阿米尔为我们做了重要的研究
Amir did vital research for us, but he left
但是因为他对他的工作存在道德疑虑  他离开了
because he had moral qualms about his work.
通常情况  钱可以解决这个问题
Normally money can overcome such obstacles.
但是在阿米尔这儿行不通
Not so with Amir.
在出租车上发生了什么
What happened on that cab ride?
阿米尔找到我
Amir sought me out.
他很生气
He was quite angry.
他以为我在他的账户里存入一万美金
He believed I had placed $10,000 in his account
作为给他施压的一种方式
as a way of pressuring him.
-但是他想错了  -等等
- But he was mistaken. - Wait a minute.
你是说阿米尔不知道钱是从哪来的
You're saying Amir didn't know where the money came from?
跟你谈话很愉快  卡塞尔先生
It's nice speaking to you, Mr. Castle.
在事件渐露端倪之时
As events unfold,
你可能会发现你们需要有我这种能力的人
you may find yourself in need of a man with my skills.
如果真的走到那步的话...
If such a moment arises...
你知道这意味着什么吗
Do you realize what this means?
如果阿米尔不知道钱的事
If Amir didn't know about the money,
那就不可能是有人付钱雇他安装炸弹
then he couldn't have been paid to build that bomb.
我能跟你们两个谈谈吗
Can I speak with the two of you, please?
我喜欢考虑周全  面面俱到
Now I like to cover my bases.
所以你想象的到  当我得知我们的人
So you can imagine my surprise when I find out one of our own
跑去跟此次调查的
is having a nonfat latte
嫌疑人喝咖啡我有多惊讶
with a suspect in this investigation.
我派了探员监视法里克·尤瑟夫
I have agents on Fariq Yusef.
如果你能让我
If you just allow me to
-解释...  -我都不知道你在这干什么
- explain-- - I don't even know what you're doing here.
你竟然去跟外国官员交谈
You go and talk to a foreign official?
如果叙利亚人是背后主谋怎么办
What if the Syrians are behind this?
你知道你干了些什么吗
Do you have any idea what you've done?
杰马尔和阿米尔不是恐怖分子
Jamal and Amir are not terrorists.
你抓错人了
You're chasing the wrong guys--
你知道你违犯了多少条法律吗
Do you have any idea how many laws you've broken?
我应该逮捕你
I ought to have you arrested.
长官  我认为卡塞尔是想说
Sir, I think what Castle is trying to say--
-贝克特探长  你知道这事吗  -是的
- Detective Beckett, did you know about this? - Yes, I did.
太令人失望了
Well, that's disappointing.
为了国家安全考虑
In the interest of national security, I'm gonna
我要把你们两个调离特别行动组
have to have the both of you removed from this task force.
-你们明白吗  -长官
- Do you understand? - Sir.
贝克特是我最好的警探
Beckett's the best I have.
卡塞尔的确总是闯祸
Now Castle can be a pain in the ass,
但是他有独到的见解
but he thinks outside the box.
这里不再是你的地盘了  队长
It's not your party anymore, captain.
我会让探员们送你们出去的
I'll have my agents escort you out.
对了  卡塞尔
Oh, and, Castle?
州长
The governor?
他从没听说过你
He's never heard of you.
阿丽克西斯和玛莎呢
Where are Alexis and Martha?
我让她们出城了
I sent them out of town.
他们知道为什么吗
Do they know why?
不知道  你联系上乔什了吗
No. You get ahold of Josh?
打不通他的电话
Couldn't get through to his cell.
他也许已经在飞机上了
He's probably already on the plane.
纤维密度600的浴帘做成的谋杀线索板
A 600-thread-count shower curtain murder board.
在我们被赶出去的时候  我拍了一张
I snapped a photo of it as we were being thrown out.
还有
And...
这  我有阿米尔的行车数据
here... I have Amir's driving data.
-这儿就像是我们的迷你分局  -不过味道好很多
- It's like our own mini precinct. - Except it smells better.
谢谢
Thank you.
卡塞尔  即使阿米尔是无辜的  杰马尔仍是有罪的
Castle, even if Amir is innocent, Jamal isn't.
他有罪是建立在阿米尔是恐怖分子这个基础上
His guilt is predicated on Amir being a terrorist.
如这个假设被推翻  杰马尔不过就是搬运工
Without that, Jamal's just another guy moving a crate.
最终一切都要回到阿米尔
No, this all comes back to Amir.
我们需要的是解决这起谋杀案
What we need to do is solve his murder.
这是搬家公司网站上的一张图片
This is a photo off the moving company's web site.
正是我们要找的那种卡车
This is the exact truck we're looking for.
好的  送到市中心警局
All right, send it downtown.
-分发给每个当班的警员  -好的
- Get it circulated to every officer on duty. - All right.
-长官  你最好看看这个  -发现了什么
- Sir, you better have a look at this. - What do you got?
技术人员刚刚锁定了杰马尔的一次性手机
Tech just got me locked on to Jamal's burner phone.
看起来他刚刚给另一部一次性手机发了短信
Looks like he just sent a text to another burner.
-你们这儿一共有几架直升飞机  -七架
- How many choppers you have in your fleet? - Seven.
好的  卡车上装有定时炸弹
All right. This truck could be parked
停在某个地方  就像俄克拉荷马市那次一样
with the bomb set to go off, just like Oklahoma City.
组织警员逐街地毯式排查
Coordinate a street-by-street grid search.
这个理论呢
Okay, how about this?
阿米尔无意间听到了一次恐怖袭击计划
Amir overhears a terrorist plot.
他安装了摄像机收集证据
He installs cameras to gather evidence,
不过他们发现了  并杀害了他
only they found out and they killed him.
那意味着有位乘客卷入其中
That means that a passenger was involved,
-一位常客  -是的
- a regular passenger. - Right,
他们提到了储藏室
and they mentioned the storage facility,
也正是因此他记下了C4121652
which is where he got the C4121652.
但是一位乘客为什么会在阿米尔面前
But why would a passenger talk about the storage unit
谈论储藏室呢  尤其是他们还打算嫁祸于他
in front of Amir, especially if they were gonna frame him?
也许...我们查错了方向
Maybe... we're going about this all wrong.
你说得对
You are right.
乘客是不会公开谈论恐怖袭击计划的
A-a passenger wouldn't openly discuss a-a-a terrorist plot,
但是司机却会
but a driver might--
跟同谋者在通电话
In the car to a collaborator,
一个人在车里
alone, on the phone.
如果阿米尔怀疑另一位司机呢
What if Amir suspected another driver?
好了  在这儿
Okay, here is...
凯文·麦凯恩的上次轮班
Kevin Mccann's last shift.
这是谋杀案前一天  你看看
This is a day before the murder, and look at that.
他在储存室公司停过车
He stopped near the storage facility
-就是放钴60的地方  -他是的士司机  卡塞尔
- where they kept the cobalt-60. - He's a cab driver, Castle.
他可能就是送乘客
He was probably dropping off a fare.
再说  他有不在场证明
Besides, he alibied out.
他也在仓库附近停留过
There he is near the warehouse, too.
这儿距离我们发现阿米尔尸体的地方只有100码
That's 100 yards from where we found Amir's body.
阿米尔去的最后两个地方
So the last two places Amir was,
凯文·麦凯恩都去过
and Kevin Mccann has been to both of them?
这不可能是巧合
There's no way that that's a coincidence.
我们至少要去看看为什么这个仓库地区
We at least have to go see why this warehouse area
这么受欢迎
is so popular.
蒙哥马利
Montgomery.
好的  知道了
Okay. Got it.
我们找到卡车的所在地了
We got a location on the truck.
我们的一位警员在地毯式搜查时发现了它
One of my guys on the grid search spotted it.
-辐射探测器有反应吗  -是的
- Did the radiation detector go off? - You bet.
在这儿停多长时间了
How long has it been sitting here?
时间不长  引擎盖还是温的
Not long. The hood's still warm.
打开
Open her up!
该死  彻查整栋大楼
Damn it! Check all the buildings.
搜查四个街区内每一个地方
Sweep every inch in a 4-block radius.
看上去没有人
Looks empty.
这儿就是凯文·麦凯恩停车的地方
This is where Kevin Mccann parked.
卡塞尔  那扇门  我们得进去
Castle, door. We gotta move.
准备好了吗  上
Ready? Go.
是杰马尔
It's Jamal.